DHRUV JUNEJA, IT Head

<u>dhruvjuneja@gmail.com</u> | (+91) 9717176712

LinkedIn: https://in.linkedin.com/in/dhruv-juneja



Award Winning – Multidisciplinary, Inquisitive and a communicative team player with 5 years of experience in delivery and Sales to a position in Business Development, Marketing and Business Strategy.

EDUCATION

B.E., Computer Science, Visvesvaraya Technological University (Reva Institute of Technology and Management, Bangalore, India) **2011**

Nokia Innovation Lab, RITM, VTU, India

May 2010 - April 2011

Cognitive based Auto reminder for Mobile, MDA using Maemo platform& Nokia device

Senior Secondary, CBSE, New Delhi 2007

Languages: English, Hindi, Spanish (Elementary)

COMPETENCIES

Non-Technical

- Business Development, Sales, Market Research, Marketing (Digital Marketing);
 Relationship Building, Qualifying Leads, Cold Calling, Negotiation, Delivering Elevator
 Pitches, Payment Collection
- IT Sales, B2B Sales, Strategy & Innovation, Client Relation, Business Analysis, Market research Analysis, Vendor-Partner Development and Management, Toastmaster, Solutioning, Microsoft Office, CRM,

Technical

JAVA/J2EE; JBOSS; Web Programming; Mainframe; Database (Oracle, MySQL, DB2);
 CMS (Magnolia, WordPress)

CERTIFICATIONS

• Inbound Certification - HubSpot

June 2016

- Got selected as one of the twenty, amongst over thousands, in Tech Mahindra's prestigious program, AIM (Achievers in the Making). Program objective was to groom associates from Delivery background and make them ready for Client facing roles. Underwent rigorous training in Sales and Business Development.
- MCP (Microsoft Certified Professional): Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3.

February 2013

WORK EXPERIENCE

Falcon Technology Services, Noida, India

May 2016 - Present

Head IT

- Aligning Business Goals, Marketing Strategy, Developing Partner and Vendor Ecosystem, Business Development & Delivery
 - Role Building complete solution partner network of international as well as local partners; P&L Management and Business Analytics platforms. CRM, Start-up consulting. Driving inside sales and Channel partnership for the organization.
 - Competitive Analysis, Business Operations, Pricing Strategy, Customer Service, Online Advertising, E-commerce, Growth Strategy, Mobile Applications; SAAS (Cloud-Based-Payroll/HRMS/ERP/Security).

- o Strategic Leadership, Strategic Thinking, Negotiations, Go-to-market strategy.
- Consulting, SME Account Management & Team Management in Enterprise for IT services, Enterprise Software, ERP Products, software Applications & Tracking, managing and communicating sales forecasts and results.
- Advising on Sales directions, competitors and market trends, including technology trends
- Marketing Professional (Hand-on-Marketing with functional and operational experience of business development with multiple clients and partners).

Skills: Learnability, Adaptability, Excellent Communication Skills, Positive attitude, People management skills, Business Development, Analytical mindset and eye for detail

Falcon Technology Services, Noida, India

Aug 2015 – May 2016

Manager Enterprise Business - Entrepreneurship

- Market research, Building Alliances, Solution partner and Vendor Management, Business Development & Delivery
 - Role Sales and Business development, identifying new opportunities while establishing current accounts.
 - Building complete solution partner network of international as well as local partners.
 Business Analysis, CRM, Start-up consulting & Cloud Solutions.
 - Competitive Analysis, Pricing Strategy, Customer Service, Online Advertising, Ecommerce, Mobile Applications
 - Strategic Thinking, Negotiations, Go-to-market strategy.
 - Consulting, SME Account Management & Team Management in Enterprise for IT services, Enterprise Software, ERP Products, software Applications.
 - Marketing Professional (Hand-on-Marketing with functional and operational experience of business development with multiple clients and partners).
 - o Complete Sales lifecycle From Market research, Identification to Deal Closure
 - Worked hand in hand with delivery and client relationship management.
 - Worked closely in marketing and brand strategizing and positioning.

Tech Mahindra (formally Mahindra Satyam), Chennai, India

 $Jan\ 2015 - Aug\ 2015$

Business Associate

- Worked as a Business Development Manager Enterprise sales, North India
 - Role: Hunter Role including identifying new opportunities, sales calls, cold visits, work with alliance teams, positioning of Tech Mahindra for the opportunity, visiting Tech Mahindra through end-to-end sales life cycle.
 - Enterprise Software, ERP Products and services for OEMs.
 - Took care of a broad Enterprise portfolio for North sales including Enterprise Mobility, Manufacturing, BFSI, HLS, Retail, Consumer Goods, FMCG, Retail, Automotive and Platform selling
- Worked in DES (Digital Enterprise Service) sales Team, Noida & Vodafone, Qatar
 - Consulting, Large Account Management, Internet of Things- IOT, software Applications
 & Cloud Solutions, Mobility
 - Responsibilities include Pre-sales and work with solution team in Noida region. Learning complete solution partner network of International as well as local partners. Involved in complete sales lifecycle Identification of opportunity, positioning Tech Mahindra for the opportunity, submitting proposal, negotiation and finally closing the deal

- **Dealer Portal Rewrite** Nissan Dealer Portal Rewrite
- 2 months
 Application Re-write from
- **CENTS (Concern Email Notification & Tracking System)** Application Re-write from technology Upgrade from updated technology stack to new cloud based server.
 - Role Requirement understanding and development of various components and modules through SDLC lifecycle.
 6 months
- Supplier Portal Rewrite Nissan Supplier Portal rewrite from old Solaris servers and Vignette
 content Management System to new Nissan standard JBOSS servers Magnolia Content
 management System, bringing NNA supplier portal up to Nissan standards while reducing annual
 support costs.
 - Role Magnolia is a new technology thus involved in understanding the Magnolia architecture and development
 11 months
- Mexico Expansion Project Identify and replicate facility specific SCM system processing jobs, programs, transactions, parameters, packaged software, interfaces, etc., to support the new plant in Manufacturing - Automotive - Supply Chain Management.
 - o **Role -** Worked through SIT (System Integration Testing) Phase 6 months
- Multi-Vin Project Impact Analysis for a Multi-Domain Change
 - o Role Phase wise Impact Analysis of components for Change Impact 6 months

Ishir Infotech Pvt Ltd (Ingenuity Gaming), Noida, India

Feb 2012 - July 2012

Asst Game Developer

Rainbow Riches, That's Magic Slot Game and Lucky Fairy Slot Game (Project Manager –
Deepak Joshi) - Online Casino Game Development in HTML5, Flash, ActionScript 3.0 to support
various peripheral devices.

*For Party Gaming merged with Bwin Digital Entertainment

INTERNSHIPS

Wipro Ltd, Bangalore, India

July 2010 - Sep 2010

 Microsoft SharePoint 2010 -training on creating website, workflow and maintenance with the default servers

Hovr Software Pvt Ltd, New Delhi, India

Jan 2009 - Feb 2009

• Website maintenance, Quality Assurance. Create technical specifications (http://www.hovr.com).

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Pat On Back for Professional Excellence.
- Pat On Back for Account's monthly magazine
- Project of the year award Certificate and gift* awarded.
- Pat On Back for Professional Excellence Award
- Manufacturing Best Team Award
- Best Team Award for LEAK Team Account Magazine for Nissan North America

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Toastmaster Dhruv Juneja **Charter member of @ Orators of TechMahindra** (Toastmasters international)
- **Founding member** and **Editor in Chief** of the Account (Nissan North America) Magazine: LEAK. (Team Size-10 and 600 Associates)
- Editor and reviewer of Location magazine Chennai Waves
- Won Technical Quizzes and C / C++ program. competitions & Member of Technical College's Forum.
- Active participation in cultural programs in school and college and Work (organizing events).